<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on IR lab @ DIKU</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on IR lab @ DIKU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Two papers accepted at SIGIR</title>
      <link>/post/sigir2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/sigir2019/</guid>
      <description>The IR lab got two papers accepted at the 42nd International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in Information Retrieval.
Unsupervised Neural Generative Semantic Hashing Fast similarity search is a key component in large-scale information retrieval, where semantic hashing has become a popular strategy for representing documents as binary hash codes. Recent advances in this area have been obtained through neural network based models: generative models trained by learning to reconstruct the original documents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two papers accepted at WWW workshops</title>
      <link>/post/www2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/www2019/</guid>
      <description>The IR lab got papers accepted at two different WWW workshops: International Workshop on Misinformation, Computational Fact-Checking and Credible Web and International Workshop of Deep Learning for Graphs and Structured Data Embedding
Neural Check-Worthiness Ranking with Weak Supervision: Finding Sentences for Fact-Checking  Automatic fact-checking systems detect misinformation, such as fake news, by (i) selecting check-worthy sentences for fact-checking, (ii) gathering related information to the sentences, and (iii) inferring the factuality of the sentences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IR lab members won the second place in WSDM Spotify Challenge</title>
      <link>/post/wsdm2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/wsdm2019/</guid>
      <description>Researchers from the IR lab competed in the Spotify Sequential Skip Prediction Challenge at WSDM Cup. The task of the competition was to predict if users will skip or listen to the music they are currently streaming. The team won the second place with a deep learning approach described in the following paper.
Modelling Sequential Music Track Skips using a Multi-RNN Approach Modelling sequential music skips provides streaming companies the ability to better understand the needs of the user base, resulting in a better user experience by reducing the need to manually skip certain music tracks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>